ALEXIS MIRANDA

Saddle Brook, NJ 07663 | alexislmiranda@outlook.com | (646) 807-7593 | linkedin.com/in/alexislmiranda | https://github.com/Grover531

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Full Stack Java Developer with over 5 years experience in business development, customer service, and sales within the technology and financial services industries. Recently completed over 450+ hours of training to gain proficiency as a Full Stack Java Developer. Interested in pursuing a Junior Software Developer role where I can continue to learn and build.

SKILLS

5+ years of combined experience in business-to-business and business-to-consumer business development, sales, and customer service

3 years of experience implementing Salesforce and SalesLoft in a revenue-generating role.

2 years of experience performing financial research including using the Bloomberg Terminal to obtain financial and economic data.

Ability to develop meaningful relationships with customers, uncover customer needs, and deliver on their expectations. Advanced Microsoft Office and Google Office skills

Proficiency with various front-end web development technologies including HTML and CSS

Proficiency in the Python programming language and Django framework

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Core Java, HTML, CSS, SQL, Python

Frameworks: Spring, Hibernate, Django

IDEs & Server: Eclipse, IntelliJ, SQL Workbench, Apache Tomcat

Databases: MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server

CRMs: Salesforce, SalesLoft

Operating Systems: Google Office Suite, Microsoft Office Suite, Bloomberg Terminal

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Consistently met the daily and monthly sales targets set by sales leadership. (Biz2Credit)
- Consistently met monthly sales targets and exceeded quarterly quota by 115 per cent. (On Deck Capital)
- Closed \$2.26MM in total deal volume within 9 months (On Deck Capital)
- Meritoriously promoted to non-commissioned officer. (United States Navy)
- Graduated top of class in Apprentice Technical Training and Center for Surface Combat Systems "A" School in the Advanced Electronics/Computer Field in the United States Navy.

EDUCATION

Per Scholas, Bronx, NY January 2021 - May 2021 (Remote) Java Full Stack Developer (450+ hours, 15 weeks)

St. John's University, Queens, NY June 2008 - May 2009 Master of Science in Accounting

September 2003 - May 2008 Bachelor of Science in Accounting and Finance

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Funding Specialist | Biz2Credit, New York, NY November 2020 – June 2021

(Technology-enabled provider of alternative financing to SMB)

• Developed relationships with clients by asking pertinent questions about their business, assessing their working capital needs, and recommending available solutions based on information provided.

- Consistently placed 60-80 unique calls to customers, as well as email communication daily.
- Owned the entire sales life cycle from prospecting to closing new customers.

Associate Account Manager | On Deck Capital, New York, NY August 2019 – July 2020

(Technology-enabled provider of alternative financing to SMB)

- Contacted inactive customers to renew relationships with On Deck for future working capital needs.
- Generated interest in On Deck's products through daily email and telephone communication.
- Prepared proposals with terms of sales and delivery dates, prepared and reviewed legal contracts, and quoted and negotiated pricing with customers.
- Worked collaboratively with Account Managers to manage pipeline and deal flow for their assigned books.

Waiter | Jitjatjo, New York, NY February 2018 – August 2019

(Technology-enabled hospitality staffing company)

- Performed server duties at upscale corporate and private events and fine dining establishments.
- Provided excellent customer service to guests and ongoing support to in-house and off-premises staff with setup, breakdown, and ad-hoc waiter duties.

Account Executive | Kinnek, New York, NY April 2016 - November 2017

(Technology-enabled e-commerce startup)

- Contacted senior executives via cold-call and cold email campaigns using Salesforce and communicated the value of the platform.
- Identified supplier pain points with senior executives and consulted them on how they could leverage the platform to address those pain points and improve their revenue and marketing goals.
- Contributed to the implementation of processes to support the sales team and improve conversion rates.
- Collaborated with product and engineering teams on product feature development based on user feedback.
- Identified market needs and opportunities collaborating with suppliers and prospects.

Customer Success Associate | Kinnek, New York, NY August 2014 - April 2016

- Provided customer support to business owners using the Kinnek platform for the first time.
- Developed relationships with small business owners and consulted them on budgeting plans for capital-intensive equipment purchases from suppliers.
- Provided purchasing support to small and medium-sized businesses with respect to budgeting and supplier interactions.
- Conducted customer insight research to improve upon the product and drive product iterations.
- Evaluated product features for user readiness prior to features going live.

Business Development | Empire State Development Corporation, New York, NY June 2012 - May 2013

(New York State governmental agency)

- Established and cultivated relationships with contractors and small business owners in New York State, helping them obtain MWBE certification.
- Provided feedback with the design, testing, and implementation of the New York State Contract System used by small business owners throughout New York State to complete the state certification process.
- Analyzed business documents, including loan documents and agreements, contractual agreements, banking records, and company financials to determine program eligibility.

Seaman | United States Navy, Great Lakes, IL January 2010 - April 2011

• Led a division of 28 recruits during Basic Training, serving as a primary assistant to Recruit Division Commanders while maintaining good order, discipline, and security within the division.